<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Plots &amp; Numbers</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Plots &amp; Numbers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Parler Posts in the UK and Ireland</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-01-17-draft-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-01-17-draft-post/</guid>
      <description>Parler is a social network that has a significant user base amount the “alt-right” and other fringe right-wing groups in the United States.
Following the US Capitol protest on the 6th January 2021 a number of service providers which provided backed infrastructure to Parler cesased their relationship with Parler and the site was forced to shut down on January 9th.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Covid data using animated graphs</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-01-01-covid-animations-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-01-01-covid-animations-r/</guid>
      <description>Animated Coivd GraphsAlthough it was a bad year for the world, 2020 was a great year for data visualisation with visualisations of both Covid-19 and US Election inescapable. Some great examples can be seen here and here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Network Analysis with R</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-10-06-network-analysis-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-10-06-network-analysis-intro/</guid>
      <description>Konigsberg Bridges
Network analysis has its origins in the Königsberg Bridge problem. The problem was to find a walk through the city that would cross each of the 7 bridges exactly once. In 1736 Euler studied a way to solve this problem mathematically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Strava Activities with R</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-09-26-visualizing-strava-activities-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-09-26-visualizing-strava-activities-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Strava is an internet service for tracking human exercise which incorporates social network features - it is sometimes referred to as “Facebook for cyclist”. Strava provides tools for analysing activities and relative performance - however there are no native Strava tools to visualise activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Shapefiles in R</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-08-01-shapefiles-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-08-01-shapefiles-r/</guid>
      <description>R and the ggplot library provide an extremely flexible framework for the plotting and visualisation of data. Plots can be extended to not just traditional line and bar plots but also to geospatial visualisations (or choropleths)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis of Tweets to Irish Banks</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-02-01-twitter-sentiment-banks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-02-01-twitter-sentiment-banks/</guid>
      <description>Analysing sentiment based on a text string is pretty classic introductory problem in the field of Machine Learning.
The idea is seductively simple - by analysing the data of publically available tweets is it possible to discern or extrapolate some additional analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
